Beatrice Binner Papers MS026
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Beatrice Binner Papers
1956 -- 1967
1956 -- 1991
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Binner, Beatrice
MS026
2.9 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized in one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains slides, photographs, maps, guidebooks, notes and newspaper clippings relating to Binner's time working for the American Red Cross. Binner, a 1943 graduate of Jackson College, traveled extensively during her tenure in the Red Cross. For instance, there are numerous photographs of her travels in Libya, Philippines, and Europe from the 1950s and 1960s. Binner's notes and newspaper clippings, such as articles about Muammar Gaddafi's 1970 coup in Libya, provide contextual information about her photographs and the locations in which they were taken.
Biographical / Historical
Beatrice Binner is a 1943 graduate of Jackson College.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Binner, Beatrice; American Red Cross -- History -- Sources.; Alumni collections
- Photographs, slides, and memorabilia, 1956 -- 1991; 1956 -- 1967; MS026.001; 2.9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs, slides, guidebooks, maps, as well as Beatrice Binner's memories of trips overseas while serving with the Red Cross. All titles beginning with "Case" refer to the slides found in that case. Boxes three and four contain kodachrome prints made from the slides found in Boxes 1 and 2.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by her cases, which is loosely chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Memoirs and overseas tour information, newspaper articles, 1956 -- 1967; MS026.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Letter to National Geographic; Finding Aid, 1956 -- 1967; MS026.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case I: Germany, Denmark, France, Holland, 1956; MS026.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Guidebook relating to Case I: Vienna, 1956; MS026.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Maps relating to Case II: Germany, 1957 -- 1958; MS026.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case II: Austria, Greece, Portugal, Spain, 1957 -- 1958; MS026.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case II: Athens, 1957; MS026.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Packaged Photographs relating to Case I: Venice, Germany, Denmark, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks and Postcards relating to Case I: Venice, Denmark, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Case I Finding Aid and Description of Overseas Tour in Germany, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Case II Finding Aid and Itenerary from trip to Venice and Greece, 1957 -- 1958; MS026.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Case I #1: To and Fro, 1956 -- 1959; MS026.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Case I #2: Hamburg; Copenhagen; April, 1957; MS026.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Case I #3: Odense; Ferry; Elsinore (Danamark); April, 1957; MS026.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Case I #4: Keukenhof Gardens; Holland; Den Haage; April, 1957; MS026.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Case I #5: Koln Dom-Rhein-April 1957; Worms-March 1957; Heidelberg-December 1956; Frankfurt-May, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Case I #6: Paris-January 1957; Afsluitdyk and Delft (Holland)-April, MS026.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Case I #7: Village; Landstuhl Germany; Landstuhl U.S. Army Medical Center, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Case I #9: Innsbruck-Austria; Bohzano-Italy; Venezia; Lido Beach; June, 1957; MS026.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Case I #10: Padova (Padua); Firenza (Florence); Rapallo; Genoa; Pisa; June, 1957; MS026.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Case I #11: Roma; June, 1957; MS026.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Case I #12: Gaeta-Italia; Pompei; Sorrento; Capri; Blue Grotto-Capri; June, 1957; MS026.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Case II #13: Trier; Luxembourg City; American Military Cemetary; Echternach; Luxembourg; September, 1957; MS026.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Case II #14: Rhein River from steamer; from chain lift at St. Boppard; from Rheinstein scholss (castle); 2 September, 1957; MS026.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Case II #16: Austrian Alps and Italian Dolomites from "Alps Express" train; Venezia; 28-29 September, 1957; MS026.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Case II #17: Dockside-Venezia; Brindisi-Italy; "S.S. Agamemnon"; Adriatic Sea; Astir Beach Resort; Greece; October, 1957; MS026.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Case II #18: Atheni; Acropolis; Parthenon; Dionysos Theatre; October, 1957; MS026.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Case II #19: Berchtesgarden (Village); Obersalzberg (Hitler's Area); February, 1958; MS026.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Case II #20: Salzburg-Austria; SkyTop-Odersalzberg (Berchtesgarden); Chiemsee Rec Center (Lake); February, 1958; MS026.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Case II #22: Genoa-Boarded; Cannes and aboard C. Bianca mano; Debarked-Lisbon; June, 1958; MS026.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Case II #23: Barcelona-Bus tour from C. Bianca mano; Gibralter; Flew to Madrid from Lisbon; June-July, 1958; MS026.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Case II #24: Lisboa; Lisboa Airport; en route Madrid; Madrid Airport; June, 1958; MS026.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Case II #25: Estoril and Cascais-fishing village; Electric Train--Lisboa-Estoril-Cascais; June, 1958; MS026.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Case II #26: Torremolinos; Malaga-Espana; June, 1958; MS026.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case III: Libya, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case III: Libya, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Finding Aid and Tour description for Case III, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case IV: Philippines, Brussels, 1958 -- 1967; MS026.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Postcards and Packaged Photographs relating to Case IV: East Berlin, 1957; MS026.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case IV: Philippines, 1956 -- 1957; MS026.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Guidebooks and Maps relating to Case IV: Brussels World's Fair, 1958; MS026.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Finding Aid and Tour descriptions for Case IV, 1957 -- 1967; MS026.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Case III #27: Sabratha; Libya (Roman Ruins); October, 1958; MS026.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Case III #28: Leptis Magna; Libya (Roman Ruins); December, 1958; MS026.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Case III #29: Suk El Guima, Libya; Near Wheelus AFB; March, 1959; MS026.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Case III #30: en route to Tebel area (mountains); Mountain village of Tefren; March, 1959; MS026.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Case III #31: Garian, Libya; Arab women at Boq (and Arab boys working at Base!); March, 1959; MS026.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Case III #32: Del Mehair Hotel; Uuadan Hotel; Grand Hotel; Palace; Sir Adrian Pelt; Boulevarde; "New City" Tripoli, 1958; MS026.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Case III #33: Medina (inner); Tripoli; Libya, 1958; MS026.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Case III #34: New City; Tripoli, Libya; Airways House; Cathedral Square, 1958; MS026.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Case III #35: Bazaar-Old City; Canadian Medical Mission; Libyan Women and Children; November, 1958; MS026.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Case III #36: Medina; Waterfront; Tripoli; Libya; April and November, 1958; MS026.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Case III #37: Cathedral Square; Castle Square; Old Fort; Tripoli, Libya, 1959; MS026.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Case III #38: Wheelus AFB; Tripoli, Libya; Misc., 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #8: Corpus Christi; Landstuhl-20 June 1957; Sigfried Line-July 1957; LAMC; June-July, MS026.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #15: Berlin-GDR (West and East Sectors); Garden of Remembrance in East Sector-USSR Mass Burial Memorial; November, 1957; MS026.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #21: Bruxelles World's Fair; Bruxelles Grand Palace and Lace Factory; April 19, 1958; MS026.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #21A: World's Fair; Bruxelles; April 19, 1958; MS026.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #39: John Hay AFB; Baguio City, Luzan; Burt and Larry Manuyan-Filipino Friends; Native Market and Burnham Park, 1966 -- 1967; MS026.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Case IV #40: Baguio City; The Philippines; Native Market; December, 1966; MS026.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Additional Slides, MS026.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles on the Military Coup in Libya by Qaddafi, 1970; MS026.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles on the Eruption of Mr. Pinatubo, June, 1991; MS026.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Beatrice Binner Photographs, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Beatrice Binner Photographs, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Sabratha Libya, Roman Ruins 67 km from Tripoli -Mag 27, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Sabratha Libya, Roman Ruins 67 km from Tripoli -Mag 27, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Leptis Magna Libya, Roman Ruins 123 km from Tripoli -Mag 28, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Leptis Magna Libya, Roman Ruins 123 km from Tripoli -Mag 28, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Suk el Giuma Libya, 6 km from Tripoli -Mag 29, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Suk el Giuma Libya, 6 km from Tripoli -Mag 29, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Tebel Mountains Libya, en route -Mag 30, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Tebel Mountains Libya, en route -Mag 30, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Tebel Mountains Libya, en route -Mag 30, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Garian Libya, Troglodytes 88 km from Tripoli -Mag 31, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Garian Libya, Troglodytes 88 km from Tripoli -Mag 31, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Fatima "Fatma" employee-Nurses quarters, Wheelus AFB, Tripoli -Mag 31, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Sir Adrian Pelt Boulevard, Tripoli-New City, Libya -Mag 32, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Sir Adrian Pelt Boulevard, Tripoli-New City, Libya -Mag 32, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Medina-Old City, Libya, 5 hour walk -Mag 33, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Airways House, Cathedral Square, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 34, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Airways House, Cathedral Square, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 34, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Bazaar, Medical Mission, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 35, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Bazaar, Medical Mission, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 35, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Waterfront, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 36, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Waterfront, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 36, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Castle, Waterfront, Tripoli-Old City, Libya -Mag 36, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Libyan-employee Seaside Officers Club, took him to Canadian Medical Mission, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Tarhuni guide-employee USAFH, 5 hour walk-Medina Suk el Guima, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Documentation on Binner Collection and trip to Libya, 1958 -- 1959; MS026.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Landstuhl-Sigfried Line, Corpus Christi -Mag 8, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Lido -Mag 9, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Florence -Mag 10, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Berlin, East Sector -Mag 15, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Austrian Alps -Mag 16, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Watzmann Mountain, Berchtesgarden -Mag 19, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Parthenon, 447 B.C. -Mag 18, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - World's Fair, 1958 -Mag 21, MS026.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - World's Fair, 1958 -Mag 21A, MS026.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Cannes -Mag 22, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Gibralter and Me -Mag 23, 1956 -- 1958; MS026.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Larry and Burt Manuyag-Baguio, The Philippines, 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Burnham Park-Baguio, The Philippines -Mag 39, 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Market-Baguio, The Philippines -Mag 39, 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Burnham Park and Market-Baguio, The Philippines (Duplicate Set), 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Mt. Province-Baguio, The Philippines -Mag 40, 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Documentation on Binner Collection and Trips in Europe and The Philippines, 1965 -- 1967; MS026.001.004.00017 (Box 4)